Stanley Matthew White II

whitematt96@gmail.com | 251-454-3487 1270 Queenstown Way Apt 303, Knoxville, TN

SUMMARY

Matt White is a recent graduate of the University of Tennessee, Knoxville with a Master of Science in Nuclear Engineering. His research included the optimization of spent nuclear fuel storage and transportation. Since 2019 he has worked with the Oak Ridge National Laboratory assisting the Used Fuel Systems group by analyzing used fuel delivery priority queues. Throughout his research he has worked on automating the production of queues for the system analysis modeling tool.

EDUCATION

University of Tennessee

Knoxville, TN

Master of Science in Nuclear Engineering; GPA: 3.56/4.0

August 2018 - December 2019

Project: Cost Implications of a Consolidated Interim Storage Facility in the Waste Management System **Project**: Design and Implementation of Spent Nuclear Fuel Allocation Priority Queues for NGSAM

Relevant Coursework: Radiation Protection, Reactor Theory and Design, Monte Carlo Analysis, Radiation Measurements and Instrumentation, Nuclear Reactor Theory, Principles of Health Physics

Auburn University

Auburn, AL

Bachelor of Science in Chemical Engineering; Minor in Nuclear Power Generation Systems; GPA: 3.42/4.0

August 2014 - May 2018

Relevant Coursework: Process Design Practice, Digital Logic Circuits, Fundamentals of Electrical Engineering, Advanced Reactor Operations, Digital Process Control, Process Economics and Safety, Chemical Engineering Analysis, Chemical Engineering Separations, Biochemistry I, Mass Transport, Heat Transfer, Chemical Reaction Engineering, Introduction to Linear Algebra, Organic Chemistry I & II, Phase and Reaction Equilibria, Physics I & II, Computer-Aided Chemical Engineering, Introduction to Thermodynamics, Linear Differential Equations, Calculus I-III, Chemistry I & II

SKILLS

• Proficient in: Python, MATLAB

Knowledgeable in: Bash Shell, LaTeX

- Technologies: GitHub, GitLab, Microsoft office
- Libraries: Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, openpyxl

EXPERIENCE

University of Tennessee

Knoxville, TN

Graduate Research Assistant

January 2019 - December 2019

- Conducted research on cost and logistic implications of interim storage facility and mined geologic repository on the integrated waste management system
- o Developed and implemented a variation to SPRINT queue prioritizing nuclear reactors over sites in NGSAM
- o Conducted research on pulse shape discrimination capabilities of a Cesium Hafnium Chloride scintillator

Thompson Engineering

Mobile, AL

Soils Testing Lab Technician

May 2015 - August 2015

- Worked closely with engineers and senior lab technicians becoming familiar with: basic soils analysis processes, equipment
 maintenance and calibration, and laboratory procedures and protocols
- Performed many ASTM soil tests including determining liquid & plastic limits, moisture content, carbonate content, compaction characteristics, particle size distribution, etc.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE & ACHIEVEMENTS

Awards.

- o Nuclear Regulatory Commission Fellowship
- o Nuclear Power Generation Systems Grant Scholarship
- o Auburn University Foundation Student Endowed Scholarship
- o Spirit of Auburn University Scholarship
- AIChE Chem-E Car Team: Placed 5th regionally in 2015, 3rd regionally and 8th nationally in 2016.